Guide to the Daly's Theatre (New York, N.Y.) Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Daly's Theatre (New York, N.Y.) Records,
1872-1899
Daly's Theatre (New York, N.Y.)
1 linear ft (in 11 volumes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, N.Y.)
4078679
Biographical Note
Augustin Daly, American playwright, adaptor, and critic, is often considered as one of America's greatest theatrical managers. He opened his first New York theater, The Fifth Avenue in 1869 and a few years later established his famous Daly's Theatre on Broadway with a stock company in which John Drew and Ada Rehan were stars and many other 19th century luminaries appeared from time to time.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ten volumes of business records connected with the operation of Daly's Theatre between 1872 and 1899. Included are cash account books recording income and expenditures, rosters of personnel, attendance books for members of the company, salary accounts, receipt books, and one volume having to do with directions for the settings for various plays.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 2 series:
Series I: Theater Record Books
Series II: Box Office Records
Subjects
Daly, Augustin, 1838-1899.; Drew, John.; Rehan, Ada.; Performing arts--New York (State)--New York.; Theaters--New York (State)--New York.; Theatrical managers--New York (State)--New York.; Theater--New York (State)--New York.; Dramatists, American.; Theater critics.; Account books.; Attendance records.; Cash books.; Financial records.; Payrolls.; Personnel records.; Receipts.; Fifth Avenue Theater (New York, N.Y.)
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
M-59
Related Material
Related material is in the Dramatic Museum Collection and the Dramatic Library Manuscript Collection.
- Series I: Theater Record Books
  - Receipts of outgoing checks or payments, May-December 1872, Jan 1873, March 1876 (Book X810.128, Volume 1)
  - Receipts of outgoing checks or payments, June 1875 - February 1877 (Box X810.128, Volume 2)
  - Cashbook-Record of expenses and balances, 1876-1884 (Book X810.128, Volume 3)
  - Stage Expenses, 1879-1884 (Book X810.128, Volume 4)
  - Box office records, 1880-1881 (Book X810.128, Volume 5)
  - Expenses, Outlays and Salaries, 1880-1882 (Book X810.128, Volume 6)
  - Cashbook, 1885-1889 (Book X810.128, Volume 7)
  - Attendance record of actors, n.d. (Book X810.128, Volume 8)
  - Individual accounts, 1895-1899 (Book X810.128, Volume 9)
  - Set designs, set sketches and list of pieces and props, n.d. (Book X810.128, Volume 10)
  - Cashbook, 1879 and 1880 (Book X810.128, Volume 11)
- Series II: Box Office Records
  Give the run, the date, the Title, the Weather and Remarks of how events may conflict with box office. For example 4 Season, 9 Week, 60 Performance, Friday November 1, 1872 Play: Road to Ruin, Weather: Fine, Remarks: Horse epidemic still prevailing. Many large political meetings.
  - Fifth Avenue Theatre Box Office Records, New York, September 4, 1872-December 27, 1873, (Vol 1: September 4, 1872-January 2, 1873; Vol 2: August 25, 1873-December 27, 1873) (Book Ms. 4, Volume 1 and 2)
  - Fifth Avenue Theatre Theater inventory, New York, n.d., (Inventory of theater furnishings and equipment) (Boook Ms. 5)
  - Fifth Avenue Theatre Property Plots, New York, n.d., (List of properties and sketches for various plays including School for Scandal which was revived in 1876, Othello, As You Like it, David Garrick. get date) (Boook Ms. 6)
  - Grand Opera House Box office records, New York, 1872-1874, (Vol. 1: August 26, 1872-June 14, 1873; Vol. 2: August 20, 1873-May 10, 1874) (Boook Ms. 7)
  - Road Company Box office records and balance book, December 18, 1882-February 26 1883, (1 vol. [Gift of Edward H. Daly, February, 1937]) (Boook Ms. 8)
  - Daly's Theatre Licenses, London, 1886-1897, (1 vol. ) (Boook Ms. 9)
  - Daly's Theatre, London Receipts; salaries; expenditures: Vol 1) First season, May 1893-July 1894; Vol 2) Second season, September 1894-August 1895; Vol 3) [Third] season, September1895-August 1896; Vol 4) Fourth season, August 31, 1986 - August 28, 1897; Vol 5) Fifth season, August 30, 1897-May 1898, Leicester Square, London, 1893-1898, (5 v. ) (Boook Ms. 10)
  - Daly's Broadway Theatre, 5th Avenue and Broadway, New York, 1873-1875, (1 v. Addresses and namesof company; list of Company, 1873-74; journal of performances Oct 19, 1874-Sept. 9, 1875; catalog of plays; cast lists Sept. 29, 1873 - Nov. 10, 1873) (Boook Ms. 11)
  - Blotter, General Accounts, New York, 1871-1874, (Advertising expenses, first 2 leaves; Blotter, September 9, 1871-March 14, 1874, p. 1-98; Cash Account for transfer, August 25, 1872-October 1872, p. 100-123) (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 1)
  - Box Office Blotter, New York, September 23, 1872-February 18, 1874 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 2)
  - Fifth Avenue Theater Box Office Receipts, New York, December 3, 1873-June 2, 1874, (The Box Office Receipts contain clippings, photographs, telegrams) (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 3)
  - Daly's Fifth Avenue Theatre Box Office Receipts, New York, August 26, 1874-June 26, 1875 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 4)
  - Daly's Fifth Avenue Theatre Box Office Receipts, New York, August 3, 1875-July 29, 1876 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 5)
  - Daly's Fifth Avenue Theatre Box Office Receipts, August 2, 1876-July 28, 1877 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 6)
  - Daly's Fifth Avenue Theatre Box Office Receipts, July 31, 1877-December 3, 1877, (Contains autograph note from Mark Twain) (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 7)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, September 11, 1882-May 5, 1883 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 8)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, October 2, 1883-April 19, 1884 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 9)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, September 15, 1884-May 2, 1885 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 10)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, September 7, 1885-April 14, 1886 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 11)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, October 5, 1886-May 28, 1887 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 12)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, October 5, 1887-April 7, 1888 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 13)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, October 9, 1888-June 8, 1889, August 16, 1889-September 21, 1889 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 14)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, October 2, 1889-May 24, 1890; August 14, 1890-September 27, 1890 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 15)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, October 7, 1890-May 24, 1891 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 16)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, November 25, 1891-May 21, 1892; September 12, 1892-October 1, 1892 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 17)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, October 6, 1892-June 3, 1893 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 18)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, August 22, 1893-april 14, 1894 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 19)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, August 27, 1894-April 15, 1895 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 20)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, September 3, 1895-April 9, 1896 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 21)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, September 9, 1896-June 26, 1897 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 22)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, August 17, 1897-May 21, 1898 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 23)
  - Daly's Theatre Box Office Receipts, August 25, 1898-June 7, 1899 (Boook Ms. 12, Volume 24)
  - Daly's Theatre Complimentary ticket stubs, New York, February 17, 1898-June 5, 1899 (Boook Ms. 13)
  - Daly's Theatre Accounts ledger, New York, April 4, 1864-March 29, 1865 (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 3)
  - Daly's Theatre Account Expenditures, New York, November 25, 1872-March 4, 1874 (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 2)
  - Daly's Theatre Accounts ledger, New York, July 24, 1877-November 24, 1877 (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 1)
  - Daly's Theatre Accounts ledger, New York, November 24, 1883-April 19, 1884 (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 4)
  - Daly's Theatre Accounts ledger, New York, September 15, 1884-May 9, 1885 (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 5)
  - Daly's Theatre Accounts ledger, New York, June 8, 1889-November 23, 1891 (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 6)
  - Daly's Theatre Accounts ledger [Theatre Cashbook], New York, November 25, 1891-November 25, 1894, (Kept by Alex. C. Milne for Aug. Daly.) (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 7)
  - Daly's Theatre Accounts ledger [Theatre Cashbook], New York, August 18, 1893-April 30, 1894 (Boook Ms. 14, Volume 8)
  - Road Company Cash book, New York, April 22, 1895-June 7, 1899, 1900, (Also contains Daly estate account to February 2, 1900) (Boook Ms. 15)
  - Fifth Avenue Theatre Salaries, New York, June 12, 1869-August 10, 1872, (Salaries of Artists of engaged by Augustin Daly from June 3, 1869, the date of the lease. Theatre opened August 16, 1869.) (Boook Ms. 16, Volume 1)
  - Fifth Avenue Theatre Salaries, New York, September 6, 1872-Jun 28, 1873, (Salaries for the fourth comedy season, 1872-1873) (Boook Ms. 16, Volume 2)
  - Salaries, August 23, 1873-March 2, 1874, (Second season) (Boook Ms. 16, Volume 3)
  - Fifth Avenue Theatre Salaries, New York, December 6, 1873-December 1, 1877 (Boook Ms. 16, Volume 4)
  - Daly's Broadway Theatre Stage Records, New York, August 25, 1873-December 15, 1873, (Lists timings with notes on performance, weather, and related events.) (Boook Ms. 17, Volume 1)
  - Daly's Theatre Stage records, New York, January 25, 1898-December 7, 1898, (Notes on performances.) (Boook Ms. 17, Volume 2)
  - Daly, Augustin Contract signed with actor Hamilton Revell, New York, 5 March 1899, (Contracts Hamilton Revell from October 1, 1890 through 1891)